（九尾）いけ　ナルト！
Go… Naruto.
てめえは失敗なんかしねえ！
You won't fail!
（ナルト）オッス！
（ガイ）おっ？
Yeah!
《また　あの力か》
That power again, huh?
カカシ　俺たちも…　んっ？
Kakashi, we ought to—!
（カカシ）やつは…　まさか…。
That man, he couldn't be…
いや…。
（ガイ）カカシ。
No…
– Kakashi…
– There's absolutely no way!
そんなバカなことが…。
（ガイ）カカシ！　聞いているのか？
Kakashi!
Are you listening?
やつを攻めるには
陽動の手数がキモになる。
The more diversions,
the better when attacking him!
俺たちも戦うぞ！
We have to join the fight!
（ガイ）お前が今
何を考えているのかは→
I've got a pretty good idea
of what you're thinking right now.
想像がつく。　俺もそうだ。
I feel the same way…
だが　そいつは置いとけ。
今は感傷に浸る暇はない。
But leave it be.
There's no time to wallow
in sentimentality.
部下だったナルトが
お前より先に突っ込んでんだぞ！
Your former subordinate, Naruto,
has already jumped into action!
バカが…。
１人で突っ込んでくるとはな！
How stupid, jumping in alone!
（ビー）ヨウヨウ！　しまった！
Yo! Yo!
Damn it!
俺１人で
突っ込んでんじゃねえよ。
I'm not alone!
九喇嘛を忘れんな。
Don't forget Kurama!
それに
ビーのおっちゃんに　八っつぁん。
There's also Octopops and Eight-o…
Bushier Brow Sensei!
ゲキマユ先生に　カカシ先生もいる！
And Kakashi Sensei too!
俺との勝負で
勝ち越しているお前が→
You've got a winning record
against me right now…
この程度で
老いぼれちゃいないはずだよな。
This better not be enough
to slow you down… Kakashi!
カカシ！
《カカシ：ナルト。
お前が俺の部下でよかったよ》
Naruto…
I'm glad you were
my subordinate!
Let's go…Guy!
いくぞ　ガイ！
我がライバル！　そうこなくては！
My dear rival!
That's what I'm talking about!
Considering my remaining chakra…
《残りのチャクラを考えても
できて　あと数発》
I only have a few shots left.
連発できない借り物の力など
恐るるに足らん。
I do not fear a borrowed power
that can't even string together
a barrage.
本当の神威の力。
The true power of Kamui…
《この神威　絶対にタイミングは…。
This Kamui…
I will not miss…
外せない！》
思い知れ！
– Now watch and learn!
– my timing!
んっ。
《術のタネがわかったところで
変わらん》
Their knowing the trick to
my jutsu changes nothing.
（ビー）入れるときに実体化するなら
出すときも実体化するはずだ！
If he has to materialize
when he takes things in,
he has to do so when
he spits things out too!
今がチャンスだぜ！
This is our chance!
That's if you can counterstrike!
反撃できればの話だが。
What is this?
《うっ…　これは！？》
Naruto!
ナルト！　こいつは
尾獣の力を拘束する→
These have Curse Marks on them
that restrain Tailed Beast power.
呪印付きだ！　いいか！
絶対に触るんじゃねえぞ！
Whatever you do, don't touch it!
ビーのおっちゃん！
Octopops!
Could you shield me for a bit?
ちょっとの間　かくまってくれ！
《影分身の術！》
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
All right, come here!
I'll be your umbrella!
わかった　来い！
俺が傘になる！
Kamui!
《神威！》
《また同じ手なら→
If it's that same trick again,
ナルトをすり抜けさせなければ
いいだけだ》
all I need to do is not have
Naruto slip through me.
What? A Shadow Clone?
なんだ　影分身か。
カカシ！
Kakashi!
うっ…。
杭のほうが速かったな。
Seems my attack was
quicker than you, Kakashi.
カカシ。　これで螺旋丸も
飛ばしそこねた。
You missed transporting away
the Rasengan…
また神威の無駄遣いだな。
…and wasted another Kamui.
Not yet!
《まだだ！　尾獣玉！》
Tailed Beast Bomb!
《少し遅い。　無駄なことを》
A bit late. How futile.
（ガイ）くっ。
おっ　お前は…。
You're—!
うずまきナルトだ！！
Naruto Uzumaki!
《そ…　そうか。
さっきの神威は螺旋丸ではなく→
I see, so that Kamui just now
wasn't transporting the Rasengan,
but the Shadow Clone itself!
影分身　そのものを飛ばしたのか。
He beat me to it…
Damn you, Kakashi!
カカシめ…　杭よりも速く！》
てめえは…！
しまった！
Who…
Damn it!
誰だ～！
…are you?!
Who Are You?
NINJA ACADEMY ORIENTATION
CHUNIN EXAM STAGE TWO
SQUAD VS. SQUAD BATTLES
KAKASHI         GUY          IBIKI
OBITO            EBISU        HAYATE
RIN               GENMA        TOKARA
CHUNIN EXAM STAGE 3
INDIVIDUAL BATTLES
CHUNIN
[TOP OF CERTIFICATE]
PLAN BY KAKASHI'S CLASSMATES
TO OBTAIN GIFTS TO CELEBRATE
HIS PROMOTION TO JONIN.
TOP SECRET MISSION.
（ミナト）今日から　カカシは　俺と同じ
上忍に就任したんだよね。
As of today, Kakashi is
a jonin just like me.
（リン）この前
ちゃんと話したでしょ　オビト。
Remember, we were talking
about this just the other day, Obito?
カカシに　プレゼントあげようって。
When we discussed
getting Kakashi a gift!
（オビト）悪い　聞いてなかった。
Sorry. I guess I wasn't listening.
（ミナト）俺は　これをあげるね。
特注クナイだよ。
Well, I got you this.
A custom-made kunai.
少し重くていびつだけど
慣れると使いやすいよ。
It's a little heavy and unconventional.
But you'll get used to it quickly.
（カカシ）どうも。
Thank you.
私は　これ！　はい！
I got you this!
Here! A personalized med kit for you.
個人用特別医療パック。
すべて使いやすいように
改良してあるからさ。
I just adjusted a few things
to make it easier to use.
サンキュー。
Thank you.
ん…。
（オビト）な…　なんだよ　その手は！
What are you holding
your hand out for?
カカシの父　サクモさんは→
Kakashi's father,
Sakumo, took his own life
中傷されて　ご自分で
自分の命を絶たれたんだ。
after everyone around him
vilified him.
（ミナト）ここからは　二手に分かれる。
This is where we go our separate ways.
さっさと行こうぜ　隊長さんよ。
Let's get going…
Captain.
《火遁　豪火球の術！》
Fire Style: Fire Ball Jutsu!
こいつは　預からせてもらう。
We'll be taking this one with us.
お前　今なに言ってんのか
自分でわかってんのか！？
Do you have any idea
what you're saying, Kakashi?!
ああ。
Yeah…
２人で
このまま任務を続行する。
The two of us have to complete
the mission alone.
And Rin? What do we do
about Rin, huh?
リンは　リンはどうすんだよ！
We'll come back for her later.
リンは　後回しだ。
We must carry out our mission
even at the expense of our comrades.
仲間を犠牲にしてでも
任務の遂行が絶対だ。
確かに　忍の世界で→
You're right. In the Ninja World,
ルールや　掟を破るやつは
クズ呼ばわりされる。
those who break the rules and
laws are regarded as scum.
けどな…。
But…
仲間を大切にしないやつは
それ以上のクズだ！
those who would abandon
even one of their friends,
are far worse than scum.
Found them!
見つけたぞ！
（オビト）カカシ…　お前どうして。
Kakashi? Why did you—?
ま！　お前みたいな
泣き虫忍者に→
Well, I certainly can't leave this up
to a crybaby ninja like you, can I?
１人で任せておけないでしょ。
カカシ…。
Kakashi…
Obito, behind you!
オビト　後ろだ！
ぐあっ！　目が…。
My eye…!
Kakashi!
カカシ！
おいカカシ　大丈夫か！
Hey, Kakashi! Are you all right?!
B-But how?
な　なぜだ。
見えるわけはない。
There's no way that
you could've seen me!
オビト　お前…。
Obito… How did you…?!
解！
Release!
カカシ　オビト…。
Kakashi… Obito…
やばい！
This is bad!
里のやつらが
なんて言おうと→
Whatever the village
or anyone else may say…
お前は　立派な上忍だ。
I think that you're a great jonin…
それが　俺の気持だ。
It's true, that's how I feel.
(受け取ってくれ))
Please accept this…
（カカシ）お前は…　オビト？
Is that you…Obito?
（ガイ）本当に　オビトなのか？
Are you really Obito?
死んだはずだろ…。
I thought you died!
間違いない…。
There's no mistake.
うちはオビトだ。
That's Obito Uchiha…
（オビト）その名で呼びたいのであれば
好きに呼べばいい。
You can call me by
that name if you want.
It means nothing to me.
俺には　なんの意味もない。
((ぐあっ　目が！
カカシ！
My eye!
Kakashi!
オビト　お前…。
Obito… How did you…?!
(ここは…　仲間は俺が守る！))
This time,
I will protect my comrade!
お前は…　あのとき…。
But that day, you…
((みんな　出口へ走れ！
Run for the exit!
うっ…。
（オビト）カカシ！
Kakashi!
（オビト）大丈夫か…。
You guys all right? Rin? Kakashi?
リン…　カカシ…。
（カカシ）オビト！
Obito!
うっ…　うぐっ…。
やめろ…　いいんだ　カカシ。
No, don't. It's okay, Kakashi.
俺は…　もう　ダメみたいだ。
I don't think…I'll make it.
体の右側は
ほとんど潰れちまって…。
My right side is completely crushed.
感覚すら…　ねえ。
I can't even feel anything
there anymore.
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
何が隊長だ！　何が上忍だ！
So what if I'm captain now?!
So what if I made jonin?!
そういや…　忘れてたぜ。
Oh, that's right, I totally forgot…
俺だけ　お前に→
I was the only one…
上忍祝いのプレゼント…
やってなかったな　カカシ…。
who didn't give you
a gift for making jonin, Kakashi.
この…
俺の写輪眼をやるからよ…。
I'm giving you my Sharingan.
カカシ…。
Kakashi, take care of Rin…
リンを頼むぜ…。
ああ…。
I will.
(オビト～！))
Obito!
《カカシ：オビト…》
Obito…
（カカシ）生きて…　いたのか…。
You're alive…
誰だってばよ！？
Who is he?
（ガイ）俺たちの同期で
木ノ葉の忍だった　うちはの男だ。
He was our classmate and
an Uchiha who was a Leaf Shinobi.
前の戦争で
戦死したはずだったが…。
We all thought he was killed
in action during the last war.
生きていたなら…
なぜ　今まで…。
If you survived, why didn't you
come forward sooner?
俺が生きていたか
どうかなんてのは→
It's irrelevant whether
I had survived or not.
どうでもいいことだ…。
しかし…　そうだな。
Although, I suppose…
なぜかと　あえて問うなら…。
If you really want an answer…
お前が　リンを…。
It's because…
you let Rin…
見殺しにしたから…。
だろうな。
die.
フッ…　早まるな。　それに…。
Relax…
Besides, what's with
that look, Kakashi?
そんな顔するな　カカシ。
俺を責めないのか？
You're not going to condemn me?
こんな　くだらない現実を
今さら責めて　何になる。
What would I gain from criticizing
this absurd reality at this point?
これから消える世界のことなどに
興味はない。
I have no interest in the affairs
of a world that shall
soon cease to exist.
カカシ先生！
Kakashi Sensei!
こいつとの間に
何があったのかは知らねえが→
I don't know what went down
between you two,
こんなとこで
落ち込んでる場合じゃねえだろ！
話はあとで　じっくり聞く！
今は　こいつの
やろうとしていることを→
止めるのが先だってばよ！
《ナルト…》
カカシ！　ナルトの言うとおりだ！
今は　世界が
俺たちの手にかかってるんだ！
お前らに話すことは　何もない。
現実に縛られたまま…
火遁…。
死ね。
爆風乱舞！
九尾の尾か。
何だ！？
（マダラ）こっちは楽しそうだな…。
（マダラ）オビト…。
＜旬の野菜が大好きな豆助＞
♪～
≫豆助
きょうのお野菜は
今が旬のアレよ？
＜　その野菜とは…＞